<Class name="Street Fighter" hitDie="10" primaryAbility="Strength">
  <Description>Your time in the streets has made you a formidable fighter. Using both brute strength and cunning, you dominate your foes with raw power and dirty moves.</Description>

  <!-- Proficiencies -->
  <Proficiency name="Armor" proficiency="Light Armor"/>
  <Proficiency name="Weapons" proficiency="Simple Weapons"/>
  <Proficiency name="Tools" proficiency="None"/>
  <Proficiency name="Saving Throws" proficiency="Strength, Constitution"/>
  <Proficiency name="Skills" proficiency="Choose two from Acrobatics, Athletics, Intimidation, Perception, Sleight of Hand, Stealth"/>

  <!-- Threat Points -->
  <Feature name="Threat Points" level="2">
    <Description>Your experience in backstreet brawls has given you access to Threat Points, which you can use to perform special moves.</Description>
    <Resource name="Threat Points" amount="1" per="Level" />
  </Feature>

  <!-- Tough Skin -->
  <Feature name="Tough Skin" level="1">
    <Description>Add your Constitution modifier to your Armor Class when not wearing armor.</Description>
  </Feature>

  <!-- Iron Fists -->
  <Feature name="Iron Fists" level="1">
    <Description>You can roll a d4 in place of the normal damage of your unarmed strike. This die increases to 1d6 at 5th level, 1d8 at 11th level, and 1d10 at 17th level.</Description>
  </Feature>

  <!-- Get Ready -->
  <Feature name="Get Ready" level="3">
    <Description>You can spend a bonus action to take the Dodge action. On your next turn, you have advantage on all attacks.</Description>
  </Feature>

  <!-- Fighting Style -->
  <Feature name="Fighting Style" level="3, 7, 10, 15, 18">
    <Choice>
      <Option name="Brawler">Gain +1d4 damage on unarmed strikes.</Option>
      <Option name="Defensive">Gain +1 bonus to Armor Class when not wearing armor.</Option>
      <Option name="Grappler">Gain advantage on grapple checks and deal 1d6 damage while grappling.</Option>
      <Option name="Aggressive">Regain 1 Threat Point whenever you hit with a melee attack.</Option>
    </Choice>
  </Feature>

  <!-- Ability Score Improvement -->
  <Feature name="Ability Score Improvement" level="4, 8, 12, 16, 19">
    <Description>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</Description>
  </Feature>

  <!-- Extra Attack -->
  <Feature name="Extra Attack" level="5">
    <Description>You can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</Description>
  </Feature>

  <!-- Dirty Moves -->
  <Feature name="Dirty Moves" level="6">
    <Description>You can spend 1 Threat Point to attempt dirty tactics like knocking an opponent prone or disarming them. Discuss these tactics with the DM.</Description>
  </Feature>

  <!-- Battle-Hardened -->
  <Feature name="Battle-Hardened" level="3">
    <Description>You can spend 1 Threat Point to gain temporary hit points equal to 1d6 + your Street Fighter level. This increases to 1d8 at 10th level, and 1d10 at 15th level.</Description>
  </Feature>

  <!-- Combat Reflexes -->
  <Feature name="Combat Reflexes" level="9">
    <Description>You can take one additional reaction each round.</Description>
  </Feature>

  <!-- Unstoppable Force -->
  <Feature name="Unstoppable Force" level="11">
    <Description>Spend 2 Threat Points to make all your attacks hit automatically during your turn.</Description>
  </Feature>

  <!-- Iron Will -->
  <Feature name="Iron Will" level="13">
    <Description>Spend 1 Threat Point to gain advantage on a Wisdom saving throw.</Description>
  </Feature>

  <!-- Tough as Nails -->
  <Feature name="Tough as Nails" level="14">
    <Description>When reduced to 10 hit points or less, you can spend 1 Threat Point to halve the damage from an attack.</Description>
  </Feature>

  <!-- Relentless Assault -->
  <Feature name="Relentless Assault" level="17">
    <Description>Spend 1 Threat Point to stun an enemy for one turn after successfully hitting them with an unarmed strike.</Description>
  </Feature>

  <!-- Master of the Streets -->
  <Feature name="Master of the Streets" level="20">
    <Description>You can attack three times, instead of twice, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</Description>
  </Feature>

  <!-- Subclass: Boxer -->
  <Subclass name="Boxer" class="Street Fighter">
    <Feature name="Boxer's Resilience" level="3">
      <Description>Spend 1 Threat Point to halve the damage from an incoming attack.</Description>
    </Feature>

    <Feature name="Knockout Punch" level="6">
      <Description>When you land a critical hit with an unarmed strike, the target must make a Constitution saving throw or be knocked unconscious.</Description>
    </Feature>

    <Feature name="Counterpunch" level="10">
      <Description>When a creature hits you with an unarmed strike, you can spend 1 Threat Point to use your reaction to counterattack.</Description>
    </Feature>

    <Feature name="Champion of the Ring" level="18">
      <Description>Gain an additional attack each round, and unarmed strikes deal an additional 1d12 damage on a critical hit.</Description>
    </Feature>
  </Subclass>

</Class>