<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>The Ancient Scribe</name>
		<update version="1.0.1">
			<file name="warlock-hate.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/MordecaiSir/elements/master/vindavia/warlock-hate.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	
	<!-- Subclass description -->

	<element name="Hate" type="Archetype" source="Vindavia RPG" id="ID_MS_VRPG_ARCHETYPE_WARLOCK_HATE">
		<supports>Otherworldly Patron</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Your patron is not a demon, god, or fey—but Hate incarnate. It simply exists, as the purest reaction to injustice, betrayal, and divine silence. Those who serve Hate do not beg for power. They demand it.</p>
			<div element="ID_MS_VRPG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HATE_EXPANDED_SPELL_LIST" />
            <div element="ID_MS_VRPG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HATE_WRATH_FUELED_SOUL" />
			<div element="ID_MS_VRPG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HATE_HATRED_TO_DIVINE" />
			<div element="ID_MS_VRPG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HATE_INTIMIDATING_HATRED" />
			<div element="ID_MS_VRPG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HATE_DEFIANCE_INCARNATE" />
			<div element="ID_MS_VRPG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HATE_HATRED_MADE_FLESH" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MS_VRPG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HATE_EXPANDED_SPELL_LIST" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MS_VRPG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HATE_WRATH_FUELED_SOUL" level="1" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MS_VRPG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HATE_HATRED_TO_DIVINE" level="6" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MS_VRPG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HATE_INTIMIDATING_HATRED" level="6" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MS_VRPG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HATE_DEFIANCE_INCARNATE" level="10" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MS_VRPG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HATE_HATRED_MADE_FLESH" level="14" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<!-- Spell Knowledge -->
	<!--$(spellcasting:list) -->

	<element name="Expanded Spell List" type="Archetype Feature" source="Vindavia RPG" id="ID_MS_VRPG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HATE_EXPANDED_SPELL_LIST">
		<description>
			<p>Hate lets you choose from an expanded list of spells when you learn a warlock spell. The following spells are added to the warlock spell list for you.</p>
			<h5 class="caption">HATE EXPANDED SPELLS</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Spell Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1st</td><td><em>command, magic missile</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>2nd</td><td><em>scorching ray, zone of truth</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>bestow curse, fireball</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>4th</td><td><em>fire shield, locate creature</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>5th</td><td><em>destructive wave, flame strike</em></td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
        <spellcasting name="Warlock" extend="true">
			<extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGIC_MISSILE</extend>
			<extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_COMMAND</extend>
			<extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_SCORCHING_RAY</extend>
			<extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_ZONE_OF_TRUTH</extend>
			<extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_FIREBALL</extend>
			<extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_BESTOW_CURSE</extend>
			<extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_FIRE_SHIELD</extend>
			<extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_LOCATE_CREATURE</extend>
			<extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_FLAME_STRIKE</extend>
			<extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_DESTRUCTIVE_WAVE</extend>
		</spellcasting>
	</element>

   <!-- Wrath Fueled Soul -->


	<element name="Wrath-Fueled Soul" type="Archetype Feature" source="Vindavia RPG" id="ID_MS_VRPG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HATE_WRATH_FUELED_SOUL">
		<description>
			<p><em>1st-level Hate feature</em></p>
			<p>When your spell reduces a creature to 0 hit points, you spread fear around with the hatred you unleashed. Use your Bonus action to force a creature of your choice up to Charisma modifier within 15 feet of the slain target to make a Wisdom saving throw (DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier). On a fail, they are frightened of you until the end of your next turn. You can use this feature a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus per short or long rest. Additionally, all your damaging spells or melee attacks count as dealing Force damage instead of their original damage type when hitting Clerics, Paladins, or Creatures with a Divine or Cosmic origin.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="{{proficiency}}/Short Rest">
          <description>Force a creature of your choice up to {{charisma:modifier}} within 15 feet of the slain target to make a DC {{wrath fueled soul:dc}} Wisdom saving throw. On a fail, they are frightened of you until the end of your next turn.

		Additionally, all your damaging spells or melee attacks count as dealing Force damage instead of their original damage type when hitting Clerics, Paladins, or Creatures with a Divine or Cosmic origin.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
          <stat name="wrath fueled soul:dc" value="8"/>
		  <stat name="wrath fueled soul:dc" value="proficiency"/>
		  <stat name="wrath fueled soul:dc" value="charisma:modifier"/>
		</rules>
	</element>

   <!-- Hatred to Divine -->

	<element name="Hatred to Divine" type="Archetype Feature" source="Vindavia RPG" id="ID_MS_VRPG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HATE_HATRED_TO_DIVINE">
		<description>
			<p><em>6th-level Hate feature</em></p>
			<p>At 6th level, Your weapon and spell attacks score a critical hit on a roll of 19 or 20 against Divine or Cosmic related creatures this range is 18-20. Starting at 14th level, this range increases to 18–20 and for Divine or Cosmic related creatures 17-20.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
          <description level="6">Your weapon and spell attacks score a critical hit on a roll of 19 or 20. Against Divine or Cosmic related creatures this is 18-20.</description>
		  <description level="14">Your weapon and spell attacks score a critical hit on a roll of 18-20. Against Divine or Cosmic related creatures 17-20.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

   <!-- Intimidating Hatred -->

	<element name="Intimidating Hatred" type="Archetype Feature" source="Vindavia RPG" id="ID_MS_VRPG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HATE_INTIMIDATING_HATRED">
		<description>
			<p><em>6th-level Hate feature</em></p>
			<p>You gain proficiency in the Intimidation skill. If you are already proficient in the skill, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules> 
		<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_OR_DOUBLE_INTIMIDATION" />
		</rules>
	</element>

   <!-- Defiance Incarnate -->

	<element name="Defiance Incarnate" type="Archetype Feature" source="Vindavia RPG" id="ID_MS_VRPG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HATE_DEFIANCE_INCARNATE">
		<description>
			<p><em>10th-level Hate feature</em></p>
			<p>At 10th level, You can no longer be easily silenced or snuffed out.
			You gain resistance to radiant damage and fire damage and have advantage on saving throws against being charmed or frightened. You cannot be frightened by Cosmic or Divine origin creatures.
			If you fail a saving throw, you can choose to reroll it once. You must take the new result. Once per long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
          <description>You can reroll a saving throw that you failed. You must use the new roll. You have Advantage on Saving Throws against beign Charmed and Frightened. You cannot be Frightened by Cosmic or Divine origin creatures.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules> 
		<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_FIRE"/>
		<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_RADIANT"/>
		</rules>
	</element>

   <!-- Hatred Made Flesh -->

	<element name="Hatred Made Flesh" type="Archetype Feature" source="Vindavia RPG" id="ID_MS_VRPG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HATE_HATRED_MADE_FLESH">
		<description>
			<p><em>14th-level Hate feature</em></p>
			<p>At 14th level, You manifest the raw presence of Hate. As an action, you unleash your true form for 1 minute. You get 1 level of exhaustion when this presence ends.
			When you deal force damage, you ignore resistance and immunity acts as resistance. Cosmic or Divine origin creatures are considered vulnerable to this damage type if they have no resistance or immunity.
			Each turn one of your attacks can deal extra 2d8 force damage.
			Enemies of Divine or Cosmic origin creatures have disadvantage on attack rolls against you while within 15 feet.
			If you reduce such a creature to 0 HP during this state, you can choose to frighten all creatures of your choice within 30 feet with DC (spell save dc) Wisdom Saving Throw. Divine or Cosmic origin creatures dont roll. and drop 1 HP instead. But you gain 1 level of exhaustion.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
          <description>As an action manifest raw presence of Hate for 1 minute. You get 1 level of exhaustion when this presence ends.
		  
		  You ignore Resistance to Force Damage and Immunities act as resistance. Cosmic or Divine origin creatures are considered vulnerable to this damage type if they have no resistance or immunity.
		  
		  Once per turn, when you hit a creature with a weapon or spell attack, the creature takes an extra 2d8 force damage.
		  
		  Enemies of Divine or Cosmic origin creatures have disadvantage on attack rolls against you while within 15 feet.
		  
		  When reduced to 0 HP, you can choose to frighten all creatures of your choice within 30 feet with DC {{warlock:spellcasting:dc}} Wisdom Saving Throw (Divine or Cosmic origin creatures dont roll). And drop 1 HP instead. But you gain 1 level of exhaustion.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

   <!-- Pact of the Hammer-->

	<element name="Pact of the Hammer" type="Class Feature" source="Vindavia RPG" id="ID_MS_VRPG_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_HATE_PACT_BOON_PACT_OF_THE_HAMMER">
		<supports>Pact Boon</supports>
		<requirements>ID_MS_VRPG_ARCHETYPE_WARLOCK_HATE</requirements>
		<prerequisite>Hate patron</prerequisite>
		<description>
		 <p>Your patron grants you a weapon of pure, unrelenting hate—a warhammer forged from cosmic spite and divine betrayal. You can summon this hammer as an action, and it disappears if it is more than 5 feet away from you for 1 minute or more. You are proficient with this weapon while wielding it.</p>
		 <p class="indent">It deals 1d4 bludgeoning and 1d4 force damage when wielded in one hand, or 1d4 bludgeoning and 1d6 force damage when wielded in two hands. When a creature takes damage from this hammer, it cannot make opportunity attacks until the end of your next turn. The bludgeoning damage dealt by this hammer ignores resistance to nonmagical bludgeoning damage; it is treated as magical for the purpose of overcoming resistance and immunity. This weapon counts as a Pact weapon for you and can be summoned or dismissed at will as part of your pact.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="Action">
		 <description>Create a hammer in your empty hand. This weapon counts as magical for the purpose of overcoming resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage.
		 Your pact weapon disappears if it is more than 5 feet away from you for 1 minute or more. It also disappears if you use this feature again, if you dismiss the weapon (no action required), or if you die.
		 It deals 1d4 bludgeoning and 1d4 force damage when wielded in one hand, or 1d4 bludgeoning and 1d6 force damage when wielded in two hands.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

   <!-- Eldritch Invocations -->

    <element name="Hammer’s Echo" type="Class Feature" source="Vindavia RPG" id="ID_MS_VRPG_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_HAMMERS_ECHO">
        <supports>Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <requirements>[level:5],ID_MS_VRPG_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_HATE_PACT_BOON_PACT_OF_THE_HAMMER</requirements>
        <prerequisite>5th level, Pact of Hammer feature</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p>Your hatred strikes not just the body, but the soul. When you hit a creature with your Pact Hammer, you may force it to make a Wisdom saving throw (DC = your spell save DC). On a failed save, the target becomes Haunted by the echo of your blow until the end of your next turn. While Haunted:</p>
			<p class="indent">The target has disadvantage on the next saving throw it makes. If it misses you with an attack, it takes force damage equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum 1).</p>
			<p>You can use this effect a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus per long rest. </p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="{{proficiency}}/Long Rest">
            <description>When you hit a creature with your Pact Hammer, you may force it to make a DC {{warlock:spellcasting:dc}} Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, the target becomes Haunted by the echo of your blow until the end of your next turn. While Haunted:
			The target has disadvantage on the next saving throw it makes.
			If it misses you with an attack, it takes force damage equal to your {{charisma:modifier}}.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

	<element name="Crush the Weak" type="Class Feature" source="Vindavia RPG" id="ID_MS_VRPG_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_CRUSH_THE_WEAK">
        <supports>Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <requirements>ID_MS_VRPG_ARCHETYPE_WARLOCK_HATE</requirements>
        <prerequisite>Hate patron</prerequisite>
        <description>
            <p>Your Warlock spells and weapon attacks deal an additional 1d4 force damage to frightened creatures.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Your Warlock spells and weapon attacks deal an additional 1d4 force damage to frightened creatures.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

</elements>
